William Edgar Borah Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Subject File, 1905-1940 (Box 754-778)
  - Nomination of Felix Frankfurter to Supreme Court, Jan. 1939, (2 folders)
  - Nominations reported, 1923-1929
  - Oil, 1933-1934
  - Oil agreements, Jan.-Mar. 1934
  - Pinchot, Amos, open letter, Apr. 26, 1937 (Box 775)
  - Pipe lines, Jan.-Mar. 1934
  - Presidential campaign, Oct. 12-30, 1932, undated, (4 folders)
  - Prohibition of advertising of liquor over the radio, 1940
  - Public land, states, 1929-1931, (2 folders) (Box 776)
  - Reconstruction Finance Corp., loan to Taber Mill, New Bedford, Mass., 1934
  - Relief, Nov. 1934-Mar. 1935, (2 folders)
  - Remarks, to 74th Congress, 2d session, Jan. 1934
  - Republican national convention, 1936
  - Republican party platform, 1928
  - Rubber, 1926
  - Sinclair Fund (Box 777)
    - Correspondence, Mar. 1928-Sept. 1936, (8 folders)
    - Financial list, 1928-1929 (Box 778)
  - Small business enterprises, 1933-1935
  - Social security, Nov. 1925-1938, (2 folders)
  - State Department, 1926-1927
  - Supreme Court decisions analyzed, 1936
  - Supreme Court reorganization
  - Tariff Act of 1930 and Jones-Costigan Act of 1930
  - Townsend Constitutional Amendment bill, 1939
  - Transportation and shipping, 1919-1932
  - Voting record on select measures, 1908-1935
- Speeches, Statements, and Articles, 1908-1939 (Box 779-812)
  Typed drafts and printed copies of speeches and statements, and copies of articles drafted by Borah.
  Arranged by type of material and therein chronologically. Supplementing the speeches and statements is reference material that Borah used in preparing his remarks. The reference material contains correspondence, printed matter, notes, reports, and newspaper clippings arranged alphabetically by subject and therein chronologically.
  - Speeches (Box 779)
    - Apr. 1908-Dec. 1922
    - Jan. 1932-June 1927 (Box 780)
    - July 1927-1928, undated (Box 781)
    - Feb. 1929-Nov. 1934 (Box 782)
    - Dec. 1934-Dec. 1939, undated (Box 783)
    - 1939, undated, and untitled (Box 784)
    - Undated and untitled (Box 785)
    - Undated (Box 786)
  - Reference and resource material, 1910-1939, undated (Box 787)
    - Agriculture, 1934
    - Antilynching bill, 1910-1939, undated, (2 folders)
    - Antiradical legislation, 1935
    - Appointments, 1914-1915
    - Armaments, 1938
    - Bankruptcy bill, 1933 (Box 788)
    - Bar examination, 1933-1935, undated, (2 folders)
    - Branch banking, 1932
    - Bureaucracy, 1914-1931, undated
    - Canadian treaty, 1935
    - Capper Resolution, Feb. 1929
    - Censorship, 1917-1919
    - Church and state, Catholic question, 1927-1929
    - Cleveland, Ohio, convention, June 1936
    - Cloture, 1913-1938, undated, (2 folders) (Box 789)
    - Concentration of wealth, 1925-1934
    - Constitution, 1924-1937, (2 folders)
    - Constitution not suspended in time of war, 1917 (Box 790)
    - Crop reduction, 1934-1937
    - Cuba
    - Currency, 1923-1933
    - Dry states, protection of, 1932-1933, (2 folders)
    - Duty of states to Constitution, 1927-1930, undated, (2 folders) (Box 791)
    - Economic conditions, 1932-1933, (2 folders)
    - Education, 1929-1935
    - Eighteen Amendment, 1919, undated (Box 792)
    - Equal Rights Amendment, 1929-1931
    - Executive power, citizen abroad, 1912-1928
    - Farm bill
      - Conference report, 1927-1938
      - Debate, 1924-1937, undated
    - Fascism
      - 1920-1937, (2 folders)
      - 1927-1938, undated, (2 folders) (Box 793)
    - Federal Corporation, 1924-1938
    - Federal labor legislation, June-July 1937
    - Federal Reserve System, 1922-1935
    - Fifteenth Amendment, 1927-1928
    - Foreign affairs
      - 1918-1936, undated, (2 folders)
      - 1937-1939, undated, (4 folders) (Box 794)
    - Fourteenth Amendment
      - Repeal of, 1936-1937
      - Seizure of telegrams, 1936
    - Freedom-of-seas after British election, 1925-1930
    - French (Box 795)
      - Debts, 1925
      - Security, 1932
      - War debt, 1931-1933
    - Great Britain versus dictators, 1939
    - History of the Supreme Court, 1909-1937, undated, (3 folders)
    - Holt underage question, 1934-1935 (Box 796)
    - Homeless children, 1929-1931
    - Hoover Plan, 1939
    - Hungry, 1930-1931
    - Individualism, 1933-1935
    - Industrial Control bill, 1933
    - Inflation, 1913-1933
    - Intolerance, 1922 (Box 797)
    - Japanese affairs, 1932-1939
    - Joplin lead monopoly, 1937
    - Jury trial, 1930
    - Labor, 1937
    - League of Nations
      - 1917-1921, (3 folders)
      - 1922-1930, undated, (5 folders) (Box 798)
      - Undated, (2 folders) (Box 799)
    - Legal briefs, 1939, undated
    - Legal question, New Deal, 1934-1935, undated
    - Ludlow Resolution, 1937
    - Miscellaneous
      - 1917-1919, undated
      - 1939, undated, (2 folders) (Box 800)
    - Monetary system, 1934-1937
    - Money, 1923-1936, undated, (2 folders)
    - Monopoly
      - 1933-1936, (2 folders)
      - 1937-1938, (2 folders) (Box 801)
      - Jackson, Robert H.., 1937, (2 folders)
    - Monroe Doctrine, 1911-1931, (2 folders)
    - Munich pact, data, 1939
    - National Recovery Act, trust laws, 1934 (Box 802)
    - Naval bill debate, 1925-1938
    - Naval race, 1936-1938
    - Neutrality
      - 1910-1939, undated, (4 folders)
      - 1939, (2 folders) (Box 803)
      - Repeal, 1939
    - Oil, 1930-1933, (2 folders)
    - O'Mahoney-Borah bill, 1937-1938
    - Opium, China, 1925
    - Philippine independence, 1932 (Box 804)
    - Philippine independence tariff, 1922-1932, undated, (3 folders)
    - Power company, 1927-1928
    - Power of removal, 1924-1935, undated
    - Railroad bill, 1933 (Box 805)
    - Relief appropriation, Jan. 1939, (2 folders)
    - Reorganization, debate, 1932-1938, (2 folders)
    - Reorganization of courts, 1932-1937, undated, (3 folders) (Box 806)
    - Robinson-Patman bill, Feb.-Apr. 1936
    - Root's formula, debate, World Court, 1925-1931, undated, (3 folders)
    - Root hearing (Box 807)
    - Russian forgeries, 1928
    - Sales tax, 1932-1939, undated, (2 folders)
    - Silver
      - 1930-1934, (2 folders)
      - 1934-1935, undated, (2 folders) (Box 808)
    - "Sit Down Strike," 1937
    - Sixteenth Amendment, 1910-1939, (2 folders)
    - South American loans, 1938-1939
    - Spain, 1938 (Box 809)
    - Speech on foreign policy, 1917-1919, undated
    - Supreme Court
      - 1920-1938, undated
      - Undated (Box 810)
      - Declares statutes unconstitutional
        - 1914-1936
        - 1936-1937 (Box 811)
        - Undated
      - States rights, 1922-1938
    - Tariff, 1929-1939, undated
    - Tax-exempt securities, 1924-1938
    - Taxes, 1931-1933 (Box 812)
    - Trade agreements, 1937
    - Wage and Hour bill, 1938, undated
    - War debts, 1929-1932
- Stenographic and Personal Notebooks, 1920-1939 (Box 813-832)
  Shorthand notebooks kept by Borah's administrative secretary listing chronologically the contents of letters received, and personal notebooks kept by Borah containing quotations from the founding fathers, facts concerning their lives from contemporary biographies, and data Borah extracted from newspapers, periodicals, and books.
  - Stenographic notebooks (Box 813)
    - Nov. 1920-June 1921
    - June 1921-May 1922 (Box 814)
    - May 1922-Apr. 1923 (Box 815)
    - Apr. 1923-Feb. 1924 (Box 816)
    - Feb. 1924-May 1925 (Box 817)
    - May 1925-Apr. 1926 (Box 818)
    - Apr. 1926-May 1927 (Box 819)
    - May 1927-May 1928 (Box 820)
    - May 1928-Aug. 1929 (Box 821)
    - Aug. 1929-Apr. 1931 (Box 822)
    - Apr. 1931-Jan. 1933 (Box 823)
    - Jan. 1933-July 1934 (Box 824)
    - Nov. 1934-Feb. 1936 (Box 825)
    - Feb. 1936-Aug. 1937 (Box 826)
    - Sept. 1937-Oct. 1938 (Box 827)
    - Oct. 1938-Dec. 1939 (Box 828)
    - Boise, Idaho (Box 829)
      - July 1924-Sept. 1931
      - Aug. 1932-Nov. 1936, undated (Box 830)
  - Personal notebooks (Box 831)
    - "Theodore Roosevelt"
    - "Alexander Hamilton", (2 vols.)
    - "Thomas Jefferson"
    - "Disarmament"
    - "Eighteenth Amendment"
    - "Memoranda"
    - "Notes–Current Topics"
    - "Important References– Congressional Record "
    - Untitled, (3 vols.)
    - "Four Powers Treaty" (Box 832)
    - "Democratic Administration"
    - "Memoranda for League of Nations Debate"
    - "Monopoly–Personal Memoranda"
    - "Corporation.. ."
- Miscellany (Box 833-868)
  Printed matter, legislative bills, scrapbooks, financial material, and biographical material.
  Arranged alphabetically by type of material.
  - Agreement, U.S. Idaho Power Co. (Box 833)
  - Articles by others
    - "America's Part in the World Court Movement"
    - On democracy, by Clark A. Corcoran
  - Bills paid
    - 1921-1922
    - 1921-1922, 1925 (Box 834)
    - 1926-1929 (Box 835)
    - 1930-1932 (Box 836)
    - 1932-1935 (Box 837)
    - 1935-1938 (Box 838)
  - Bills pending, 1929-1931, 1934, 1938 (Box 839)
  - Biographical material (Box 840)
    - General
    - Thesis on Borah
      - McNally, James W.
      - Robertson, Thomas, Jr.
  - Biographical sketch of Gerald P. Bodily
  - Brief concerning Lausanne Treaty
  - Briefs of letters concerning relief
  - Claims, legislation concerning
    - Gnash, Stephen
    - Gustafson, Jacob
    - Hochlander, John
    - Larking, W. R.– Walter S. Hogan
    - Annual depression of grain market (Box 841)
    - Borah-Formes Licensing bill
    - Bultland, Daniel
    - Dearce, C.W.
    - Dividing Idaho judicial districts
    - Fair labor
    - First session (Pipeline Oil)
    - Fourth Division: Idaho District, U.S. District County
    - Indian Irrigation Project
    - Members of Congress acting as attorneys
    - Montana
    - Neibaur, Thomas C.
    - O'Mahoney-Borah Licensing bill
    - St. Joe National Forest
    - Transportation of oil
    - Washington, Oregon, and Idaho, jurisdiction over boundary rates
    - Wood pulp
  - Editorials
  - Form letters, congressional legislation, (1 folder) (Box 842)
  - Fragments
  - Galley proof of foreign relations hearings, 1936
  - Hearings of investigations of concentration of economic power
  - Legislative bills (Box 843)
  - Loan application by Big River Irrigation District, Mackay, Idaho, 1932
  - Memoranda, general
  - Memoranda concerning John Gray and Pierce Butler
  - Negative photostats
    - Correspondence, telegrams, photographs, and statements in the Borah Papers, University of Idaho, Moscow, Idaho
    - Newspaper clippings at the University of Idaho, Moscow Idaho
  - Newspaper clippings (Box 844)
  - Newspaper clippings (Box 845)
  - Newspaper clippings (Box 846)
  - Newspaper clippings (Box 847)
  - Plan for San Francisco, Calif., water supply (Box 848)
  - Poetry
  - Postcards, (2 folders)
  - Printed matter (Box 849-860)
  - Scrapbooks (Box 861)
    - Aldrich, Louis See Container 754, Alien actors' immigration
    - Statements and clippings by and about Theodore Roosevelt
  - Haywood, William Dudley, trail for murder, 19107 (Box 862)
  - Signature books, inhabitants of Nyíregyháza, Hungary (Box 863)
  - Special legislation (Box 864-865)
  - Speeches by others (Box 866)
  - Speeches by others (Box 867)
  - Thesis on corporate power
  - Works Project Administration, projects in Idaho, 1938-1939 (Box 868)
- Borah for President Committee Papers, 1935-1936 (Box 869-881)
  Correspondence, ballots, cartoons, lists, editorials, financial material, newspaper clippings, press releases, and poetry.
  Arranged by type of material. The correspondence is arranged alphabetically by state and occasionally subdivided by individuals within the state. Material other than correspondence is grouped by type under miscellany.
  - Alabama (Box 869)
  - Arizona
  - Arkansas, Lonzo A. Ross
  - California, (2 folders)
    - Campbell, E. Weaver, (2 folders)
    - Evans, William E.
    - Fish, Hamilton
    - Inman, J. M.
    - Sunderlin, Charles A.
  - Colorado, Parriott, James D. (Box 870)
  - Connecticut
  - Delaware
  - District of Columbia
  - Florida
  - Georgia
  - Idaho
    - Haga, Oliver O.
    - McKaig, Ray
    - Whitla, Ezra R.
  - Illinois, (3 folders) (Box 871)
    - Anderson, Sumner S.
    - Chiperfield, Burnett M.
    - Cook, Edgar J.
    - Crowe, Robert E.
    - Eicheinbaum, William
    - Lauterbach, B. C.
    - Levinson, Salmon O.
    - Nowinson, Richard (Box 872)
  - Indiana, Morton S. Hawkins
  - Iowa
    - Clark, C. F.
    - Maher, Frank
  - Kansas, W. N. Smelser
  - Kentucky
  - Louisiana, Edmond E. Talbot
  - Maine
  - Maryland
  - Maryland (Box 873)
    - Elliott, David L.
    - Katz, Harry L.
    - Work, George E.
  - Massachusetts, Robert M. Washburn
  - Michigan
  - Minnesota, Peter S. Rask
  - Mississippi
  - Missouri
  - Montana (Box 874)
  - Nebraska
    - Nelson, Robert A.
    - Simmons, Robert G.
  - Nevada
  - New Hampshire
  - New Jersey, (2 folders)
    - Frawley, J. A.
    - Gates, Russell C.
    - Stokes, Edward C.
    - Sweeney, Algernon T.
    - Trimble, Henry W.
  - New Mexico
  - New York, (4 folders) (Box 875)
    - Adelman, Daniel
    - Fish, Hamilton, Jr., (2 folders)
    - Gannett, Frank E.
    - Macy, W. Kingsland
    - Sanford, Henry R. (Box 876)
    - Smith, W. Ward
    - Ziegler, William, Jr.
  - North Carolina
  - North Dakota, O. E. Erickson
  - Ohio, (4 folders)
  - Ohio (Box 877)
    - Knight, J. S.
    - McCollough, Roscoe C.
    - Morgan, Daniel E.
    - Murphy, Frank
  - Oklahoma
  - Oregon, Thomas R. Hamer
  - Pennsylvania, (3 folders)
  - Pennsylvania (Box 878)
    - Fish, Hamilton, Jr.
    - Jones, J. Webster
    - Jurst, T. Duncan
    - Kurtz, J. Banks
    - Pinchot, Gifford
  - Rhode Island
  - South Carolina
  - South Dakota
    - Christopherson, C. A.
    - Kehm, Harry C.
  - Tennesse (Box 879)
  - Texas, (2 folders)
  - Utah
  - Vermont
  - Virginia
  - Washington
  - West Virginia (Box 880)
  - Wisconsin
    - Nagler, L. B.
    - Nelson, Philip E.
    - Prehn, Arthur W.
  - Wyoming
  - Miscellany (Box 881)
    - Ballots, cartoons, political advertisements
    - Borah Club, Republican clubs, lists
    - Cleveland, Ohio, convention
    - Colored record
    - Editorials
    - Emblems, slogans
    - Financial
      - Bank accounts
      - Checks
      - Statements
    - Form letters
    - Miscellaneous letters and notes
    - Newspaper clippings, (2 folders)
  - Poetry
  - Press releases
  - Songs
  - Speeches
  - Townsend leaders, list
- Correspondence of Grace Hileman, 1923-1936 (Box 882)
  Letters sent and received.
  Arranged chronologically by month.
  - Correspondence, 1923-1926 (Box 882)